Contact

hopecarney@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/hopecarney (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
ICU
ACLS
Nursing

Hope Carney RN

Experienced Emergency Department RN

Louisville, Kentucky Area

Summary

Experienced registered nurse with 13 yrs emergency department experience, 1 yr cardiac catherization experience, 3 yrs clinical coordinator experience with cardiology group. Some charge nurse and management experience as well. Always looking to expand my knowledge and experience. BLS, ACLS, PALS, TNCC, CEN.

Specialties: Emergency Department

Experience

Baptist Health Louisville Charge Nurse Emergency Dept October 2006 - Present (13 years 10 months) Louisville, Kentucky

Charge RN in a busy Emergency Department. Responsible for all aspects of emergency nursing care of patients infant to geriatric. Emphasis in stroke and cardiac patients.

Jewish Hospital Medical Center East
Associate Nurse Manager Emergency Department (4/2004-12/2004)
Charge Nurse (5/2003-4/2004)
May 2003 - December 2004 (1 year 8 months)

Instrumental in the initial set up of a new free-standing emergency department. Responsible for obtaining medications, supplies, and equipment before the opening of the emergency department and during everyday operation. Responsible for the set up and everyday operations of the Medical Center East division of Jewish Hospital EmployCare for after hours work comp injuries, including overseeing drug screening, breath alcohol testing, and return to work instruction.

Cardiovascular Associates
Clinical Coordinator
March 2002 - October 2004 (2 years 8 months)

Accompanied cardiologists on weekend hospital rounds. Prepared charts with information such as patient history, vital signs, labs, and other test results. Scheduled patients for stress tests and cardiac catherizations. Arranged for admission for patients transferred from outside facilities.

Norton Audubon Hospital 7 years 2 months

Staff Nurse Cardiac Catherization Lab April 2002 - August 2004 (2 years 5 months)

Responsible for direct patient care before, during, and after cardiac catherization, PTCA, and ICS. Assisted physicians in the cardiac catherization procedure.

Staff Nurse/Relief Charge Nurse Emergency Department July 1997 - March 2002 (4 years 9 months)

Responsible for all aspects of patient care from infants to geriatrics in a busy emergency department. Emphasis in cardiac and stroke patients. Relief charge nurse responsible for management of staff on night shift in the emergency department.

Education

University of Louisville BSN, Nursing · (1993 - 1997)